livetext.com 2017-06-06

# LiveText, Inc. Privacy Statement - LiveText

### LiveText, Inc. is committed to protecting your privacy.

* * *

## PRIVACY STATEMENT

We have prepared this Privacy Policy to describe our practices regarding the personal information that may be collected from users of our websites. By submitting personal information through our websites or services, you expressly consent to the processing of your personal information in the United States in accordance with this Privacy Policy. LiveText, Inc. attempts to collect only limited amounts of information. The use of personal information collected through our websites or services shall be limited to the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. We reserve the right, in our sole discretion, to modify this Privacy Policy at any time by posting such changes here. Your continued use of any of our websites or services following the posting of any changes to this Privacy Policy indicates your acceptance of such changes. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you are not authorized to access or otherwise use any of our websites or services.

We are not responsible for your organization’s collection, use, or disclosure of your personal information. Please contact your organization to better understand your organization’s privacy practices. LiveText, Inc. will retain personal information we process on behalf of organizations for as long as needed to provide services and as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. LiveText, Inc. uses only de-identified and aggregated data for its own purposes.

* * *

## PCI / PII (PAYMENTS)

LiveText, Inc. utilizes a 3rd party vendor – Authorize.net for processing all of its credit card transactions. The LiveText, Inc. application passes on these transactions directly to Authorize.net and no LiveText, Inc. systems store any sensitive credit card information on them internally. Authorize.net is a fully certified PCI compliant firm. In addition, LiveText, Inc. has recently undergone a formal PCI assessment itself (for added certification purposes) performed by iPayment, Inc. The Validation Number of the PCI Assessment is: IPMT42236958100015360512.

* * *

## DATA YOU PROVIDE TO US

We collect information from you, such as first and last name, e-mail and mailing addresses, title, institution name, and username/password when you create an account to log in to our network. We also may retain information on your behalf, such as files and messages that you store using your account. If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail, we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail. When you participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information. We also collect other types of personal information and demographic information that you provide to us voluntarily.

* * *

## DATA COLLECTED VIA TECHNOLOGY

To make our services more useful to you, our servers collect information from you, including browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet, which may vary from session to session), domain name, unique device identifiers, information about how you use our sites, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit. Like most Internet services, we automatically gather this data and store it in log files each time you visit our site or access your account on our network. We may link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. Materials and content a user puts on LiveText, Inc. is not shared without permission. Copyright for such content belongs to the user.

* * *

## ANALYTICS

We use analytics services to help analyze how users use the site. These services use cookies and scripts to collect and store information such as how users interact with our site, errors users encounter when using our apps, device identifiers, how often users visit the site, what pages they visit, and what other sites they used prior to coming to the Site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve our site and services.

* * *

## FORUMS

Our website offers community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

* * *

## USE OF YOUR DATA

Personal information and content you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. LiveText, Inc. uses your personal information in the following ways: to create and maintain your account; to identify you as a user in our system; to operate, maintain, and improve our websites and services; to personalize and improve your experience; to send you administrative e-mail; to respond to your comments or inquiries; to send you surveys, promotional communications about our products and services with your permission; to protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity; and to make telephone calls to you, from time to time, as a part of secondary fraud protection or to solicit your feedback with your permission.

* * *

## DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

LiveText, Inc. does not intend to disclose any of your personal or identifiable information without your permission. We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described as follows or with your express consent.

* * *

## FAMILY EDUCATION RIGHTS AND PRIVACY ACT (FERPA)

Through employee education, training and risk analysis efforts, LiveText, Inc. adheres and conforms to the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) regulation. All user data is strictly not “publicly releasable” and therefore not available to any external parties. Additionally, within the platform any “Non-Directory” data is viewable to only Account Administrators who have been designated by the client with permissions to view this data.

* * *

## SAS70 / SSAE16 CERTIFICATIONS / AUDITS

LiveText, Inc. fully manages and administers its entire server and network system environment – these activities are not outsourced to any external or 3rd parties. LiveText, Inc. does utilize a 3rd party (Equinix) for co-locating / hosting its PRODUCTION systems. The cabinets / cages which LiveText, Inc. leases are only accessible to authorized personnel. Equinix undergoes rigorous and regular security and IT audits (i.e. SSAE16 certification superseding the SAS70 certification).

* * *

## AFFILIATES

Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “AFFILIATES”), we may in the future. We may share some or all of your information with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

* * *

## OTHER DISCLOSURES

LiveText, Inc. may disclose information about you if it believes such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with laws or to respond to lawful requests and legal process; or (b) protect or defend the rights, safety, or property of LiveText, Inc., users of our websites or services, or any person, including to enforce our agreements, policies, and Terms of Service, or (c) in an emergency to protect the personal safety of any person.

* * *

## YOUR CHOICES REGARDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION CHOICES

When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in e-mails you receive from us, or by contacting us directly. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can typically remove and reject cookies from our websites with your browser settings. If you remove or reject our cookies, it will affect how our websites and services work for you.

* * *

## SECURITY OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

LiveText, Inc. takes reasonable steps to protect your personal information in an effort to prevent its unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Despite these measures, you should know that LiveText, Inc. cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with personal information. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. Any content you post while using the services is at your own risk.

* * *

## TERMS OF SERVICE

In addition to this Privacy Policy, your use of any of our websites or services is also governed by our [Terms of Service](https://www.livetext.com/terms-of-service/).

The terms of our Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service constitute the entire agreement between you and LiveText, Inc. with regard to any LiveText, Inc. websites or services.

* * *

## GOVERNING LAW

The laws of the State of Illinois shall govern this Privacy Policy regardless of your location. You hereby expressly consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in the federal and state courts located in Cook County, Illinois, for all matters or disputes arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy or any provision, use, storage, publication or dissemination by any person of any data or information governed by it.

* * *

## CONTACT INFORMATION

LiveText, Inc. welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at [edu-solutions@livetext.com](mailto:edu-solutions@livetext.com).
